<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns="https://w3id.org/okp4/ontology/vnext/schema/credential/digital-service/declaration/" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#">
  <rdf:Property rdf:about="https://w3id.org/okp4/ontology/vnext/schema/credential/digital-service/declaration/hasIdentifier">
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">has identifier</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">
  The URI that identifies and locates the Digital Service.
  
  The URI serves a dual purpose:
  1. **Identification**: It provides a unique identifier for the Digital Service, ensuring that each service can be distinctly recognized within the dataverse.
  2. **Endpoint**: The URI acts as the access point or endpoint for the Digital Service. It specifies where the Digital Service can be accessed and how interactions with the service should be initiated. 
  </rdfs:comment>
    <schema:domainIncludes>
      <rdfs:Class rdf:about="https://w3id.org/okp4/ontology/vnext/schema/credential/digital-service/declaration/DigitalServiceDeclarationCredential">
        <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Digital Service Declaration Credential</rdfs:label>
        <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">
  Digital Service Declaration credentials serve as a testament to the declaration of a Digital Service within the dataverse.
  
  A Digital Service is a multifaceted entity integral to the processing and transformation of Digital Resources. It functions not merely as an operator on these resources, but as a critical structural and functional unit in the knowledge creation process.
  
  These services distinguish themselves through their ability to interact dynamically with Digital Resources, facilitating the generation of new knowledge by providing network interfaces for user engagement. They encompass a variety of forms, ranging from Infrastructure Services, which lay the foundational groundwork for efficient resource sharing and transformation, to Digital Resource Processing Services, which manage complex processes for transforming digital resources. This includes various algorithms and models, from simple logical rules to advanced AI-driven algorithms and machine learning models, thereby catering to the unique needs and objectives of diverse tasks.
  </rdfs:comment>
      </rdfs:Class>
    </schema:domainIncludes>
    <schema:rangeIncludes rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#anyURI"/>
  </rdf:Property>
</rdf:RDF>
